# James Ryan

james4165@hotmail.com Mobile Ph: 0430 710 408 <u>jamesryan.azurewebsites.net</u>

I have 5 years of programming experience including 2 years of web programming. My education is as a Civil Engineer though I am very interested in making a career change to software development.

Have a look at my portfolio for examples of my experience: jamesryan.azurewebsites.net

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

2013 to Nov 2015 Graduate Civil Engineer (Full-Time)

**Real Serious Games** 

# Key Accomplishments:

- Use of Microsoft Excel for manipulating large volumnes of construction schedule data and other data from companies such as Leightons, Thiess and Lend Lease
- Programming of various tools used in the office using C#, WPF and VBA and communicating regularly with programmers
- Providing mockup drawings for modifications to 3D Models
- QA of software
- Communicating construction drawings to 3D modelers

2011 to 2013 Trainee Structural Engineer (Full-Time)

**NBR** Australia

## Key Accomplishments:

- Carried out structural design of cold-formed steel portal frame buildings and various types of residential buildings.
- Structural drafting of various commercial and industrial portal frame buildings and residential homes and associated detail drawings
- Developed in-house structural engineering software used for analysing loads and calculating bracing, member and connection requirements for portal frame buildings
- Development of 3D portal frame model and load generation software in Excel/VBA using Multiframe Automation.
- Used many different Australian Standards and product manuals
- Other duties such as general administration and document handling/organisation

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

2009 to 2013 Bachelor of Engineering majoring in Civil and Construction

Queensland University of Technology

2005 to 2006 **Diploma of Mechanical Engineering** 

Moreton Institute of TAFE

Resume: James Ryan

#### **Extra Curricular Achievements**

- Winner of 2011 Baulderstone National Icons design competition
  - 1st place out of over 150 entries nation wide
  - Winning entry consisted of conceptual redesign of the Story Bridge and 700 word report
- Designed and published two Android applications on Google Play
  - "EasyBeam" a structural engineering application
  - "Where in the World", a Google map and streetview based guessing game

# **Programming Skills**

I have been programming on my own personal projects and at previous workplaces for almost 5 years and have experience with :

- Node.js, html, sass/css, javascript, SQL Server, Azure Websites, Backbone.js. Also some PHP and Laravel
- C# and WPF
- Java for Android
- Very proficient with Microsoft Excel and VBA, and knowledge of Microsoft Word
- Some knowledge of R for statisical analysis

#### **Interests**

- Computers & Programming(Web, C#, VBA)
- Sharemarket

- Video Games
- Making guitar/electronic songs

### **REFEREES**

**Dr Greg Darcy** 

NBR Australia

Ph: 0421 671 454

# **Rod Etto**

Etto Designs and Drafting Ph: 0411 564 529

## **Professor Tommy Chan**

Queensland University of Technology (QUT) tommy.chan@qut.edu.au

Resume: James Ryan

#### WEB PROGRAMMING PORTFOLIO

Below are some of my latest web programming projects. You can see the live versions here <a href="http://jamesryan.azurewebsites.net/#/portfolio">http://jamesryan.azurewebsites.net/#/portfolio</a>

## Galaxi



This was an experimentation with animations using the popular Greensock and Scrollmagic javascript libraries. I created the art in Inkscape.

HTML, SASS, jQuery

#### **Technicorp**



A demo home page for a fake company. Uses parallax scrolling images and SVG images for slanted navigation and menu screens.

HTML, SASS, jQuery

# Neeonn



This was a concept for a social storyboard sharing website. It features user accounts, a search page to search public storyboards and tools to create storyboards which includes a HTML canvas. There is also an andoird app with the same features and storyboards are synced between the website and app.

SQL Server, PHP/Laravel, HTML, SASS, Backbone, Cordova

## Scattertale



Scattertale is a website for creating and sharing rearrangeable articles. It features user accounts, a search page to search public articles and tools to create articles. It is currently on hold.

SQL Server, Node.js, HTML, SASS, Backbone

Resume: James Ryan

Below is the result for a Javascript test I completed recently for a recruiter.

